Hi, everyone. I'm Shizue Izawa.
I've come back for the Bon Festival.
I wonder how Slime-san is doing.
I decided to visit because I was
wondering about that, but...
That tiny town is a bustling
city of so many monsters now.
I've heard rumors
that Slime-san is living in
a form that resembles my own.
It's a little embarrassing.
Why is it always clothes like these?!
It looks so nice on you, Great Rimuru!
Rimuru
We still have more!
Please, no!
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Slime Diaries
Day 6: Changes
So on that note,
tomorrow and the next day will be
a holiday called the Bon Festival.
Bon Festival? What's that?
A day to give thanks to our ancestors
and reconfirm our bonds with
our families and clans.
Our town doesn't have
much history of its own,
but all of you living here
have histories, right?
That's true.
Indeed...
So once a year, you should
have a party with your own kin
to talk about your people's origins
and tell stories of the past
with your families and siblings.
Our clan's own...
...party?!
And of course, though we're all different
races, this whole town is a family.
Once you know about your history,
you can teach each other about it
and deepen your bonds with
everyone you know now.
What a good idea, Great Rimuru!
Great Rimuru!
Great Rimuru, what does "Bon" mean, anyway?
Uh, good question...
I don't know, either.
Oh, right, I know!
It's something about putting tons of
food on your plate and having fun!
I love it!
That clears it right up!
You're the best, Great Rimuru!
Aw...
The Bon Festival is a period
in July when the ghosts of—
Okay, we don't need to make it complicated!
Today's the day I've been waiting for:
the day Rimuru's Retreat is ready for me.
Yay! New tatami!
It's smaller than all the
other houses in town.
It's not fit for you, Great Rimuru.
This tight, relaxing space that feels
like a secret base is just what I wanted!
Nothing fancy, nothing pretentious,
no way to get bored!
It's like the cheap apartment I lived
in when I first moved to Tokyo.
Maybe I haven't changed
on the inside at all...
Well, wouldn't want to
forget where I came from.
Why are you making such a sad face?
I have to spend my day off fishing with you?
We haven't had a single bite yet.
That's because you're holding
on to wicked thoughts.
The paths of swordsmanship and
fishing lead to each other.
You must become one with nature
and melt into the flow of mana.
Then not only the fish, but any
enemy you face is no match for...
See Ya
To think the likes of Gobta could trick me...
Seeing my pupils mature is
both joyful and saddening.
Starting tomorrow, you'll train ten times
as hard to match your rate of growth!
I was just kidding! I'm right here!
When I first met him, he looked
like some wild brigand,
but now he's a brilliant military commander.
Yo! What'cha doin'?
Reviewing the organization of our forces.
Wow, sounds tough.
The town has grown,
and so has its population.
And thanks to Hakuro's training,
everyone's skills have improved dramatically.
These peaceful times with
no major wars to fight
are the best time to build an
invincible army with no weaknesses.
Pardon me.
I've brought tea.
You've changed, huh?
I'm still the same me I was in the past.
Nope, you've changed.
Slime Diaries
Slime Diaries!
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Don't forget here, Brother.
Right!
A True Story: Secret Agent Soei
A True Story: Secret Agent Soei.
The work of a secret agent is very diverse.
Escorting...
Spying...
Check this out!
With all this, we can live
it up for a good while!
As well as investigation...
and assassination.
There is no room for personal affairs.
He must be silent,
cool-headed, and flawless...
all for his master's benefit.
That is his fate.
As for the resistance in
the Kobold settlement...
We must report the nuance of
the conversation accurately.
Do you remember what was said?
Yes, every single word.
Then will you be the head of the
west or the head of the east?
West
East
Huh? U-Um, the head of the west, then...
The straight man, eh?
You've become quite confident.
S-Straight man?
I'll be the funny man, then.
End all lines with "arf."
G-Got it... arf.
Come in!
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Slime Diaries
Um... Great Rimuru found that hilarious.
The young master looks more
and more like our late lord.
Sure does.
Sir Benimaru looks much stronger
than he did back in our village.
Don't flatter me. It's all
because of Great Rimuru.
Hey, Hakuro...
What was my father like when he was young?
Back then, our village was
also small, and our lord...
He could not begin to compare to you.
He was far worse.
I've never heard about this...
I would imagine not.
It was long before you two were born.
What fine weather we're having...
I'm a slime.
So if I'm a slime,
why do I look like a human?
There's a reason.
Back when this was still
a small, simple town,
she came here from the Kingdom
of Blumund with her companions...
Why'd you have to poke at its nest?!
We're gonna die!
I couldn't help it! I was curious!
Enough chatter! Just run!
...along with trouble.
Kingdom of Blumund
What's the matter?
I'm not sure.
I dreamed about Shizu for
the first time in a while.
Oh, I did, too.
So did I.
We should visit her grave...
Except I guess she doesn't have one.
It was the leader of the monster
city that laid her to rest.
I wonder how Rimuru's doing.
We should, at least, say a
prayer while we're here.
Shizu, we're doing just fine as adventurers.
We're dirt poor, but we're having fun.
Please continue to watch over us.
Of course. Good luck.
So, what was Shizu like in your dream?
Actually, she was in the form of
a bunny being chased by monsters.
Oh, yeah, that look suited her.
Wait, wait! Something's wrong here!
She was into that kind of thing.
You've got it all wrong!
Lake Siss  Home of the Lizardmen
Ah, the Bon Festival, you say?
What a lovely holiday.
Yes.
And I've brought this,
from the outsider of our clan.
Come closer.
Of course.
I see. So he is doing well.
Yes.
He hasn't changed, but he
is working his hardest.
Honestly, that boy...
Good work.
Thank you.
Then, I will now take my leave.
Wait.
By the way, Soka...
You have received a marriage proposal.
Look! What do you think of this guy?
I respectfully decline.
Huh?!
Then how about this—
No, thank you.
No?! Then this one?!
Wait, wait, wait! This one is good, too!
Come on! Just pick a card, any card!
This is why I never want to come back home.
Puppet Nation Distave
There is a king in this world
who rules over monsters:
a Demon Lord.
Yes, I am the ruler of Distave...
The king.
It is nearly time for Walpurgis...
Time to carry out my plan.
Demon Lord Carrion may be crude,
Animal Kingdom
of Eurazania
Beast King Carrion
but he has an earnest sensitivity
and an eye for the genuine.
Frey joined us quite abruptly,
Winged Nation
of Fulbrosia
Sky Queen Frey
but with her femininity and delicate
nature, she can sympathize with me.
And...
Milim Nava.
The Destroyer
Milim Nava
Demon
Lord
She may be the oldest of the Demon Lords,
but I have already looked into
her tendencies carefully.
All measures have been taken.
Now, come at once, Demon Lords,
for the sake of my ambition!
The Walpurgis Plan
Preparations to Serve
My own special-made scones
will soon be ready.
Complete
Clayman really seems to be enjoying himself.
Armed Nation of Dwargon
A slime who rules over monsters, you say?
Slime...
That goes best with vinegar sauce.
Huh?
Forgive me, but I prefer brown sugar syrup.
I agree with the king.
I like it nice and cold, with cayenne pepper.
Wait, all of you!
I'm talking about a slime!
Lady Jane, please tell them!
I've always preferred brown sugar syrup!
Brown Sugar Syrup
Then it's settled.
Very well!
I will be the judge myself!
Ah, er...
I will assemble the Pegasus Knights.
Huh? What's the matter, Great Rimuru?
I just had a really bad feeling...
I'm going to go get some fresh air.
Keep Our Wells Clean
Rigur!
Oh, Great Rimuru.
Let me have a cup, too.
Help yourself. It's from underground,
so it's nice and cold.
Thanks!
Wow, the town sure is a
lot more impressive now.
Not long ago, I couldn't
have even imagined this.
Hey, I was thinking...
When I first met you guys in the forest...
Strong one, do you have business here?
If you hadn't spoken to me that day,
this town might never have been built.
When you put it that way...
you might be right.
It's kinda funny, huh?
I guess it is.
Right?
We gotta take care of it!
Yes. Today is the day of the Goblins'
cultural festival, after all.
So today is, uh... what was it again?
Completion of our first
phase of urban planning!
Building of the big bath!
Uh... The clearing of our third farm...
Blacksmith Shop
Blacksmith shop.
Oh! The establishment of
Kurobei's blacksmith shop!
We reached our hipokute
herb cultivation quota!
The sixth Goblin cultural
festival, and... uh...
a bunch of other things to celebrate!
Anyway, let's just have a toast!
Cheers!
Drink up!
Great Rimuru!
Hey, good work!
I can still drink more!
Great Rimuru!
You forgot the completion
of my compilation of poetry!
Ah, that's included in the "other"!
Shizu-san was an Otherworlder, like me.
She was summoned into this world
while Japan was fighting a war,
and a spirit granted her a long life.
In the end, with what
little life she had left,
she rejected the spirit's
destructive impulses
and saved many people's lives...
then she passed on,
leaving her final wish with me.
Yes, my body is what I look like after
laying Shizu-san to rest within me.
Wait, what am I wearing?!
It looks fantastic on you!
Rimuru
Let's try on lots more!
No! No way!
Sorry, Shizu-san.
I had so much to do, I ran late.
It's not incense, but I
made something similar.
I threw it together in a rush,
but it feels like Bon, right?
The body and skills I inherited
from you have been a huge help.
I hope I get to thank you someday,
but I might not have the
strength for that just yet.
Sorry.
Don't worry.
As long as you're living a fun
life in my form, that's enough.
I thought my life was over,
but you gave me a wonderful
gift I never could've expected.
But... go easy on the embarrassing
outfits if you can, okay?
Tell that to those two!
Who... was that?
The winds change, and the seasons turn.
Multiple plots squirm together
and become entangled.
A great wave approaches the
world enclosed within them.
And...
Wh-What now?!
My diary's definitely going
to have a full belly!
To Be Continued
Preview
Oh, you start showing up next week.
Aw, but I already made
such a grand entrance...
Next time, "Here Comes the Demon Lord!"